Austin FitzGerald

Software Engineering Major

1021 61st ST Lisle, IL 60532(630)-956-6602

☐ fitzgeralaus@uwplatt.edu

AFitz.space

Summary

Software Engineering major with experience in leadership positions, well developed techniques in conflict resolution. Consistently punctual in the development and design of both web and non-web applications to given specifications. Motivated to devise creative solutions to abstract problems in a team setting and capable of quickly adapting to changing requirements. Highly organized and results-driven work ethic, defined by extensive preparation and communication. Excellent knowledge of the SDLC and experience working in Agile teams. I value software quality!

Education

Bachelor of Software Engineering

2017 - 2021 (Expected)

University of Wisconsin-Platteville, Platteville Wisconsin

Emphasis in Engineering Management. UW-Platteville has an ABET accredited Software Engineering program.

Work experience

Resident Assistant

January 2019 - Present

University of Wisconsin - Platteville - Residence Life

Leadership position in a campus residence hall. Responsible for overseeing over 25 undergraduate students and providing information on university resources and developing an educational atmosphere.

Undergraduate Researcher

September 2018 - Present

University of Wisconsin - Platteville - CSSE Department

UW-Platteville Summer Undergraduate Scholars Program 2019 Researcher. 1 out of 10 students from the university to receive the grant. Worked under Dr. Selent to research, design, and develop multiple predictive models used to predict student struggle in future CSSE courses.

Previously involved in multiple research groups under Dr. Alkhushayni. Primary group developed an Android application developed to be used for personal health data entry, storage, and analysis. Implemented a unique set of chronic disease risk assessments.

Lab Assistant

September 2018 - Present

University of Wisconsin - Platteville - CSSE Department

Provides lab assistance for students enrolled in Computer Science courses in a courteous and efficient manner. Experienced with policies of the Computer Science department in regards to code quality, assessment, and plagiarism. Trained and tested on The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 in order to act as a liaison for the University.

Intern August 2018

Perritt Capital Management

In-office and remote data collection as well as analysis. Most work was done through Microsoft Excel. VBA macro creation for mass data formatting and chart creation.

Freelance Programmer

2015 - 2018

Self Employed

Web development, design, and non-web programming for local businesses, peers, and online freelance contracts. Clear documentation and follow ups with customers, along with guided support and timely communication

Student Employee

September 2017 - January 2018

University of Wisconsin - Platteville - Dining Services

Opening of multiple dining stations, including allergy-free food preparation. Followed guidelines for cooking to ensure quality meals and a safe environment for employees. Major involvement in closing of dining locations, in addition to the kitchen and dish room. Worked alongside education at the university.

Crew Member

February 2016 - February 2017

McDonald's, Lisle Illinois

Experience with multiple positions such as food preparation, cashiering, inventory management, dish washing, and closing the restaurant. Developed time management skills to meet quick food preparation times as a crew member and temporary shift manager. Balanced correspondence skills with customers, with attention to conflict prevention. Awarded Employee of the Month in April of 2016.

Organizations

Volunteer Mentor

September 2018 - Present

Westview Elementary 3rd & 4th Grade Coding Club

Free coding club for 3rd and 4th grade students at Westview Elementary in Platteville, Wisconsin. Utilized the curriculum provided by code.org and Google's CS First.

Student Member

September 2018 - Present

Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)

World's largest scientific and educational computing society. Attendee of on campus meetings and events such as the 2018 and 2019 North Central NA Regional Contests for the ICPC.

Skills

Front End Web: CSS, JavaScript, Wordpress

JavaScript Frameworks: ¡Query, Materialize, ChartJS, Bootstrap v3/v4

Programming Languages: Java, C#, C++, Python **Markup Languages:** HTML, Markdown, LaTeX **Software:** JIRA, Git, Microsoft Excel, Adobe Photoshop

Also have some experience with GNU/Linux and PHP. Will be proficient with Database Design and Implementation by May, 2020. I love data!

Awards

- Under a team lead by Dr. Douglas Selent, received 2nd place in the poster competition at the annual WiSys Innovation Showcase. Research titled "Applying Predictive Models to Course Curriculums for Early Struggling Students."
- The Surface Mount Technology Association (SMTA), per their LinkedIn, is "an international network of
 professionals who build skills, share practical experience and develop solutions in electronic assembly
 technologies, including microsystems, emerging technologies, and related business operations." In May of
 2018 I was awarded the scholarship based on my experience in electronics and programming. I received
 the award at the SMTA Wisconsin Chapter Vendor Day in Milwaukee.
- Recipient of the 2019 Lombard Lodge No. 1098 A.F. & A.M. Masonic Scholarship.
- Created and reported an exploit that would allow users, mostly students, to bypass a web filter and access illicit content. The web filtering system was installed as a permanent extension for Google Chrome, as an alternative to common DNS filtering. The policies were broken by reverse engineering the original extension, and was reported to the parent company before source code was released. (June 2017)